<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<marc:collection xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/standards/marcxml/schema/MARC21slim.xsd">
  <record>
    <leader>00000npc a2200000 u 4500</leader>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
      <subfield code="a">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">dacs</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="245">
      <subfield code="a">District of Columbia Public Library Records</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Architecture</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Library of Congress Subject Headings</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Libraries</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Library of Congress Subject Headings</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">District of Columbia. Public Library</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Librarians</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Library buildings</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Library of Congress Subject Headings</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Trusts and trustees</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Library of Congress Subject Headings</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">142 boxes</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">145 Linear feet</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="099">
      <subfield code="a">040</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="555">
      <subfield code="a">Finding aid online:</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">http://washingtoniana.dclibrary.org</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="4" ind2="2" tag="856">
      <subfield code="z">Finding aid online:</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">http://washingtoniana.dclibrary.org</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="546">
      <subfield code="a">English</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="545">
      <subfield code="a">In 1894 General Adolphus W. Greeley solicited funds for the creation of a public library in Washington, D.C. In 1897 the subscriber supported Washington Free Public Library was opened as Congress had been unwilling to fund a public library for the District of Columbia (District) since it felt the Library of Congress was sufficient to meet residents’ needs. In 1898 at the urging of Theodore W. Noyes, editor of The Evening Star, and other prominent District citizens, Congress finally appropriated $6,720 to fund a public library and the District Commissioners appointed a nine member library Board of Trustees. The Washington Free Public Library merged with the newly created Public Library and the first publicly funded library in the District opened with 15,000 books at 1326 New York Avenue NW. Andrew Carnegie pledged $250,000 to erect a new library building for the District if Congress would provide funding to maintain the library. On March 3, 1899, Congress passed an act to accept Carnegie’s offer and set aside federally owned land at Mt. Vernon Square as the site for the new central library building. Carnegie increased his total donation to $350,000 on September 28, 1899. The cornerstone for the building was laid on April 23, 1901 and on January 7, 1903 the Carnegie Library opened with elaborate festivities which included President Theodore Roosevelt and Carnegie in attendance. The first official branch library of DCPL was built in 1911 in the Takoma Park neighborhood with funds provided by Carnegie. However, from the earliest days of DCPL many neighborhoods had temporary or subbranch libraries operating in storefronts or schools before receiving a stand alone branch. Two more Carnegie funded library branches were erected; Southeast Neighborhood Library in 1922 and Mt. Pleasant Neighborhood Library in 1925. Northeast Neighborhood Library, Georgetown Neighborhood Library, Petworth Neighborhood Library, and Southwest Neighborhood Library were all added between 1932 and 1942. During the post-war period of the 1950s and 1960s DCPL increased services as part of the Model Cities Programs and a bookmobile was in operation to serve underserved neighborhoods. Between 1953 and 1968 branches added included the Cleveland Park Neighborhood Library, Anacostia Neighborhood Library, Woodridge Neighborhood Library, Washington Highlands Branch (later closed), Tenley-Friendship Library, Francis A. Gregory Neighborhood Library, Dorothy I. Height/Benning Library, Palisades Neighborhood Library, Capitol View Neighborhood Library, West End Neighborhood Library, and Chevy Chase Neighborhood Library. In 1972 the Central Library at Mt. Vernon Square was replaced by the Martin Luther King Jr. Memorial Library (MLK) at 9th and G streets, NW. The new central library was designed by Ludwig Mies van der Rohe and was eight times the size of the original Carnegie Library. Between 1975 and 2012 branches added included Wathat T. Daniel/Shaw Neighborhood Library, Parklands-Turner Neighborhood Library, Lamond-Riggs Neighborhood Library, Juanita E. Thornton/Shepherd Park Neighborhood Library, Northwest One Neighborhood Library, Deanwood Neighborhood Library, Rosedale Neighborhood Library, and William O. Lockridge/Bellevue Library. </subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="561">
      <subfield code="a">Material were transferred to the Washingtoniana Collection as part of a regular library retention policy.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="2" ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">The archive contains the official records of the Washington Free Public Library and the District of Columbia Public Library (DCPL). The records include photographs, slides, correspondence, scrapbooks, posters, newsletters, blueprints, maps, architectural drawings, meeting minutes, internal memoranda, audiotapes, reports, payroll ledgers, financial information, and other official files. The records document the operations and projects of the library’s directors, board of trustees, divisions, departments, central library, and branch libraries. The D.C. Community Archives is the official repository of the records of offices, divisions, departments and trustees of DCPL. The Library follows a records management program and records schedules for transfer of permanently valuable historic records to the archive.</subfield>
    </datafield>
  </record>
</marc:collection>

