<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<marc:collection xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/standards/marcxml/schema/MARC21slim.xsd">
  <record>
    <leader>00000npc a2200000 u 4500</leader>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
      <subfield code="a">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">dacs</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="245">
      <subfield code="a">Francis A.Gregory Genealogical Collection</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">African Americans</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Library of Congress Subject Headings</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Genealogy</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Library of Congress Subject Headings</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Education</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Public schools</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Library of Congress Subject Headings</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Teachers</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Library of Congress Subject Headings</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Music</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Library of Congress Subject Headings</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">3 Linear feet</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">6 Boxes</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="099">
      <subfield code="a">005</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="555">
      <subfield code="a">Finding aid online:</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">http://washingtoniana.dclibrary.org</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="4" ind2="2" tag="856">
      <subfield code="z">Finding aid online:</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">http://washingtoniana.dclibrary.org</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="546">
      <subfield code="a">English</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="545">
      <subfield code="a">The Shaed Family was a prominent family of educators and professionals in Washington, D.C.  After their marriage in 1900, Gregory and Cenos Shaed moved from Florida to Washington, D.C. where Mr. Shaed became a printer with the Government Printing Office.  The Shaeds had six children, Alice Evelyn, Ernestine Pamela, Helen Virginia, Dorothy Lee-Louise, Eunice Jane, and Gregory W., Jr.  All of the Shaed daughters were graduates of Miner Normal School and became teachers for D.C. Public Schools.  Gregory, became a physician after graduating from Howard Medical School in 1934 and practiced in Florida, Michigan, and Virginia. In 1971, Alice and Ernestine Shaed Elementary School located  at 301 Douglas Street, NE was dedicated to honor the  Shaed sisters’ careers at D.C. Public Schools. The school was closed in 2011. The Baltimore family was a prominent family of educators in Washington, D.C.  Thelma Lane Baltimore, educated at Miner Normal School and Howard University, taught in D.C. schools ending her career as Director of Elementary Education in D.C. Charles Baltimore was a coach and vocational educator who taught at the Armstrong Training School and was a principal at Bell Vocational High School in the 1960s. </subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="561">
      <subfield code="a">In the mid 1980s, Nora D. Gregory, a member of the Library’s Board of Directors, proposed the development of a genealogical collection to document the history of certain prominent African-American families in Washington, D.C. history.  Eunice Shaed donated the Shaed family papers to the Library in 1988. There is no documentation surrounding the donations of the Baltimore or Hoffman materials. </subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="2" ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">The collection was artificially created by the Library and  consists of the Shaed and Baltimore family papers; as well materials regarding Elzie Hoffman.  It includes photographs, programs, published books, biographies, letters, certificates, diaries, scrapbooks, clippings, and other family memorabilia.  The collection has been divided into series by family.  Many of the items are related to Washington, D.C. educational institutions that most of the members of the families attended; Dunbar High School, Miners Teachers College, and Howard University. A biography of Clarence Sumner Greene, his wife Evelyn Gardiner, and Greene family photographs are also included. </subfield>
    </datafield>
  </record>
</marc:collection>

