<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<marc:collection xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/standards/marcxml/schema/MARC21slim.xsd">
  <record>
    <leader>00000npc a2200000 u 4500</leader>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
      <subfield code="a">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">dacs</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="245">
      <subfield code="a">Chillum Heights Citizens Association Records</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Neighborhoods</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Library of Congress Subject Headings</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">1.5 linear feet; 4 boxes</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="099">
      <subfield code="a">042</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="555">
      <subfield code="a">Finding aid online:</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">http://washingtoniana.dclibrary.org</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="4" ind2="2" tag="856">
      <subfield code="z">Finding aid online:</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">http://washingtoniana.dclibrary.org</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="546">
      <subfield code="a">English</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="545">
      <subfield code="a">The Chillum Heights Citizens Association was known as the Citizens Association of Rock Creek Church Road and Vicinity when organized in April 1894.  A few months later, the name was changed to Woodburn Citizens' Association and finally to the Chillum Heights Citizens' Association.   The records include correspondence, minutes, clippings, reports, and financial materials from the Chillum Heights Citizens Association.  There are also topical files and other items relating to the Federation of Citizens Association.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="2" ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">Contains meeting minutes, correspondence, financial materials, membership lists, and clippings regarding the activities of the Association.  Collection also includes topical files on such subjects as D.C. home rule and suffrage, juvenile delinquency, crime, civil rights, racism, D.C. budget, the Rock Creek expressway as well as items from the Federation of Citizens Association and Neighbors Inc.  Folders are arranged into three series:  administrative materials; correspondence and minutes; and topics. The folders in the administrative and topical series are arranged alphabetically and folders in the correspondence/minutes series are arranged chronologically. </subfield>
    </datafield>
  </record>
</marc:collection>

