<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<marc:collection xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/standards/marcxml/schema/MARC21slim.xsd http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim">
  <record>
    <leader>00000npcaa2200000 u 4500</leader>
    <controlfield tag="008">180202i19111975xx                  eng d</controlfield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
      <subfield code="a">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">eng</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">dacs</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="0" ind2="7" tag="041">
      <subfield code="a">eng</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">iso639-2b</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="049">
      <subfield code="a">DWP</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="099">
      <subfield code="a">064</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="245">
      <subfield code="a">Albert W. Atwood Collection,</subfield>
      <subfield code="f">1911-1975</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">11</subfield>
      <subfield code="f">linear feet; 8 boxes</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="2" ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">The collection consists of scrapbooks containing Albert W. Atwood’s articles and editorials from The Saturday Evening Post and The National Geographic Magazine, as well as three books and a poster from the DC Public Library.  Also included are photographs, articles, and awards. 

The control file for this collection contains a title index of Mr. Atwood’s articles and editorials from The Saturday Evening Post.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="545">
      <subfield code="a">Albert W. Atwood was born in Jersey City, New Jersey in 1879.  He graduated from Fredonia (NY) State Normal School in 1899 and from Amherst College in 1903.  Albert W. Atwood was a leader in the scholarly, journalistic and philanthropic communities in Washington, DC in the early twentieth century.  He served as President of the Board of Trustees for the DC Public Library, was President of the Cosmos Club, and was a regular contributor to The Saturday Evening Post and The National Geographic Magazine, as well as various local newspapers and journals.  He also wrote a biography of Senator Francis G. Newlands and a history of Gallaudet College.  He died in 1975 in Washington, DC.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="546">
      <subfield code="a">English.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="561">
      <subfield code="a">The Albert W. Atwood Collection was accessioned into the DC Community Archives in 1998.  The collection of materials was acquired by the DC Community Archives prior to 1998, but little information about the materials exists, save for a note in two of the volumes that read “Property of Mrs. Yates.”  The assumption is that Mr. Atwood created the materials, but this cannot be verified.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Business</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Libraries</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Library of Congress Subject Headings</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="852">
      <subfield code="a">DWP</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="4" ind2="2" tag="856">
      <subfield code="z">Finding aid online:</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">http://washingtoniana.dclibrary.org</subfield>
    </datafield>
  </record>
</marc:collection>

