<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<marc:collection xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/standards/marcxml/schema/MARC21slim.xsd">
  <record>
    <leader>00000npc a2200000 u 4500</leader>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
      <subfield code="a">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">dacs</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="245">
      <subfield code="a">Mary G. Ziegler Papers</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Education</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Urban renewal</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Library of Congress Subject Headings</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Gentrification</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">9 boxes</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="099">
      <subfield code="a">010</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="555">
      <subfield code="a">Finding aid online:</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">http://washingtoniana.dclibrary.org</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="4" ind2="2" tag="856">
      <subfield code="z">Finding aid online:</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">http://washingtoniana.dclibrary.org</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="546">
      <subfield code="a">English</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="545">
      <subfield code="a">Mary G. Ziegler was a teacher and then principal of Forest Haven, formerly known as the District Training School for almost 40 years.  The school was established in 1925 by a pioneering psychiatrist and his wife as a farm colony and hospital at the Fort Meade Army Base for the training of the mentally retarded.   Mrs. Ziegler began working at the School in 1928 soon after it opened and did not retire until 1962.  The D.C. government dedicated and opened a new training facility for the mentally retarded in 1961 and named it the Mary G. Ziegler School to honor Mrs. Ziegler’s “continuous service and unceasing devotion.” </subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="2" ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">The papers which cover  Mrs. Ziegler’s career as an educator of the mentally retarded at the District Training School in Laurel, Maryland which later became Forest Haven School.  Papers covering Mrs. Zeigler include photographs of activities and events at the school, publications regarding the training of the mentally retarded, press releases, programs, a newsletter, correspondence, awards, published books, and certificates.  Also of particular importance are seven scrapbooks of clippings, photographs, programs, invitations, letters, and other memorabilia prepared by Ms. Zeigler on the District Training School, which covers the years 1924 through the 1960s.</subfield>
    </datafield>
  </record>
</marc:collection>

