<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<marc:collection xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/standards/marcxml/schema/MARC21slim.xsd">
  <record>
    <leader>00000npc a2200000 u 4500</leader>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
      <subfield code="a">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">Describing Archives: A Content Standard</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="245">
      <subfield code="a">Washington Star Papers</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Business</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Evening Star Newspaper Co.</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Library of Congress Subject Headings</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">American newspapers</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Library of Congress Subject Headings</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Newspapers</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Library of Congress Subject Headings</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">169 Boxes</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">87 Linear feet</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="099">
      <subfield code="a">061_001</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="555">
      <subfield code="a">Finding aid online:</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">http://washingtoniana.dclibrary.org</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="4" ind2="2" tag="856">
      <subfield code="z">Finding aid online:</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">http://washingtoniana.dclibrary.org</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="546">
      <subfield code="a">English</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="545">
      <subfield code="a">The first issue of the Washington Star, then known as The Daily Evening Star, was published as a four-page daily on December 16, 1852.  The daily’s founder and first editor was Captain Joseph Borrows Tate, a printer and officer in the Washington Militia.  Tate believed that Washington newspapers published at the time were mouthpieces for the major political parties, and wanted to publish an independent newspaper “free from party trammels and sectarian influences, [that]… will preserve a strict neutrality.” Tate sold the paper within six months to William H. Hope and William Douglass Wallach; who became the sole owner by 1854.  In its early years the paper fought for city improvements and although its editor was a traditional southern democrat, he and his newspaper supported Lincoln’s fight to preserve the Union.  In 1867, a three-man consortium, Crosby S. Noyes, Samuel H. Kauffmann, and George W. Adams, acquired the paper. In the late 19th century the Star championed many civic improvements in D.C. including public works improvements; a free public library; the construction of Union Station; and the replacement of Potomac River marshes with the Tidal Basin and Potomac Park.  Harry P. Godwin became the newspaper’s first city editor in 1881 and by 1890 the paper included an associate editor, managing editor, and wire news editor.  In 1881 the Star moved from 11th and D Streets, NW site to a new location at 11th Street and Pennsylvania Avenue, NW. The Star also purchased a corner building at the same site and by 1900 staff moved into the remodeled corner structure.  By 1921 the Star had erected a 10-story annex on the 11th Street NW side known as the Star building.  The paper began publishing the Sunday Star in 1905.  Samuel H. Kauffmann died in 1906 followed by Crosby S. Noyes  in 1908.  Descendants of the Noyes,  Kauffmann, and Adams families continued to own and run the paper until the 1960s. In 1937 the Star became the first Washington paper to own a radio station, WMAL, and the first paper to own a television station, WMAL-TV, in 1947.  During World War II, four Star reporters covered the news overseas, and it published an overseas edition for GIs. In 1952 the Star celebrated its 100th birthday at the peak of its influence and circulation with parties and special publications. The Star was characterized by the public as a local newspaper that emphasizing the coverage of local issues, service to the community, and support of civic causes. In 1959, the Star moved from its historic home to a newly constructed five-story plant at 2nd Street and Virginia Avenue SE.  By the mid-1960s the Star was considered a conservative paper. Circulation and reputation trailed behind the Washington Post.  In 1972 the Star purchased the Washington Daily News, one of the few remaining competing newspapers in the city. For a short period of time following the merger, various names for the paper appeared on the masthead. Eventually by the late 1970s the paper settled on the Washington Star.  In 1975,  Houston, Texas banker Joseph L. Albritton bought substantial shares of stock in Star Communications, Inc. from the three controlling families for $28.5 million. The Star’s financial troubles continued and in 1978, Albritton sold the Evening Star Newspaper Co. to Time, Inc. for $20 million.  Time Inc. invested over $80 million in the newspaper but on August 7, 1981 the paper  ceased operations and published its last issue. </subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="561">
      <subfield code="a">After the close of the paper in 1981, all assets were absorbed by the Washington Post, who transferred custodial rights for the collection and the photograph morgue to the Library in 1983. The agreement between the Washington Post and the Library made the library a publication rights granter.   </subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="524">
      <subfield code="a">Please use the following credit line when using images from the Star: Copyright Washington Post; reprinted by permission of the DC Public LibraryWhen citing manuscript materials from the collection, please use the following citation:D.C. Public Library, Washingtoniana Division, D.C. Community Archives, Collection 61, Papers of the Washington Star.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="2" ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">The papers of the Washington Star consist of a variety of formats.  These materials were gathered over 130 years of the newspaper’s publication in Washington, D.C.  The collection includes information on the day-to-day operations,  leadership changes, labor disputes, marketing reports, historical materials, and other topical files and reports.  Materials in the collection include: correspondence; financial records; newsletters; newspapers; clippings; advertising and marketing reports; legal documents; photographs; negatives; slides; scrapbooks; audiocassettes; videocassettes; awards; certificates; and programs.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="540">
      <subfield code="a">The Library is licensed by the copyright holder, The Washington Post, to sell reproductions of Star staff photographs and to permit their use.  Because the Library and the Star do not hold copyright for wire service and certain other images in the collection, researchers must obtain permission from the copyright holder for reproductions of those images.</subfield>
    </datafield>
  </record>
</marc:collection>

