<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<marc:collection xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/standards/marcxml/schema/MARC21slim.xsd">
  <record>
    <leader>00000npc a2200000 u 4500</leader>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
      <subfield code="a">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">dacs</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="245">
      <subfield code="a">Mayor's Mansion Debate Collection</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">1.67 linear feet; 4 boxes</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="546">
      <subfield code="a">English</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="545">
      <subfield code="a">The Mayor’s Mansion Debate Collection focuses on a proposed track of land which was to be donated by Mrs. [] Casey to Washington, DC with the stipulation that the property be designated for use as the mayor’s official residence. While many local residents and government officials were appreciative of the proposed gift, feelings remained mixed. Among the concerns raised by local residents and city officials were questions about financing the maintenance and security of the property, whether the city and National Park Service should engage in a proposed land-swap, and if moving the mayor’s residence to the Georgetown neighborhood sent the wrong message to the residents of Washington, D.C. by making the mayor appear distant or elitist.

As community groups and conservation organizations weighed in on the matter, the debate of accepting the proposed gift remained undecided, and in late 2003, the Casey Foundation withdrew the offer, and donated the land to the Salvation Army. 

In the aftermath, Howard Bray, a local resident who actively involved in the ongoing debate surrounding the controversial project, used the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) to request inter-office correspondence and reports relating to the Mayor’s Mansion Debate from the National Park Service, Washington City Council, and the Mayor’s Office
</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="561">
      <subfield code="a">Mr. Howard Bray donated this collection, which he acquired from several government agencies and non-profit groups under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA).</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="2" ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">Housed in thirty-eight folders in four boxes, the collection consists primarily of correspondence (e-mails, faxes, letters) reports, testimonies, maps, copies of deeds, and appraisals from both government agencies and private citizens. </subfield>
    </datafield>
  </record>
</marc:collection>

