<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<marc:collection xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/standards/marcxml/schema/MARC21slim.xsd http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim">
  <record>
    <leader>00000npcaa2200000 u 4500</leader>
    <controlfield tag="008">181001i18061995xx                  eng d</controlfield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
      <subfield code="a">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">eng</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">dacs</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="0" ind2="7" tag="041">
      <subfield code="a">eng</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">iso639-2b</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="049">
      <subfield code="a">DWP</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="099">
      <subfield code="a">135</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="245">
      <subfield code="a">Hilda Mason, Statehood Party Collection,</subfield>
      <subfield code="f">1806-1995</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">20</subfield>
      <subfield code="f">cubic feet; 20 boxes</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="3" ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">Hilda Mason was a steadfast member of the DC Statehood Party as well as a supporter of the development of the University of the District of Columbia. The bulk of the Hilda Mason Statehood Party Collection dates from the 1970s to the mid-1990s and documents Mason's stalwart commitment to the party. The collection contains committee files (most notably for the Committee on Self-Determination), drafts of the Constitution of the State of “New Columbia,” files from DC Statehood Party conventions, and files from the Leadership Conference on Civil Rights. Also included are business cards from various DC leaders, correspondence, news clippings, reports, and speeches.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="2" ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">The bulk of the Hilda Mason Statehood Party Collection dates from the 1970s to the mid-1990s and documents Mason's stalwart commitment to the party. The collection contains committee files (most notably for the Committee on Self-Determination), drafts of the Constitution of the State of “New Columbia”, files from DC Statehood Party conventions, and files from the Leadership Conference on Civil Rights. Also included are business cards from various DC leaders, correspondence, news clippings, reports, and speeches.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="540">
      <subfield code="a">Some material may be copyrighted or restricted. It is the patron's obligation to determine and satisfy copyright or other case restrictions when publishing or otherwise distributing materials found in the collections.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="545">
      <subfield code="a">Hilda Howland Mae Mason was born in Altavista, (Lynch Station, Virginia) on June 4, 1916. She attended Virginia Seminary in Lynchburg and St. Paul's College in Lawrenceville. Mason relocated to Washington, DC in 1945. She later enrolled at Miners Teachers College and earned her undergraduate degree in 1952. She was a teacher, counselor and administrator in the DC public school system for 19 years, until she was elected to the Board of Education from Ward 4. She served from 1972-1977, after which she was appointed to complete the term of Julius Hobson, Sr., the at-Large member of the DC City Council. After completing Hobson’s term, she won an at-Large seat on her own merit. Mason was a champion of education in DC as chair of the Council’s Education, Libraries and Recreation Committee (1981-1997), the Local, Regional and Federal Affairs Committee, the Human Services Committee, and the Judiciary Committee. To date, her tenure on the City Council remains the longest term of service in the city’s history. Mason was also a steadfast member of the DC Statehood Party, as well as a supporter of the development of the University of the District of Columbia. The law school library bears her name and the name of her husband, Charles N. Mason, Jr., a graduate of Harvard University and Howard University Law School.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="546">
      <subfield code="a">English.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="561">
      <subfield code="a">Hilda Mason donated her collection of DC Statehood Party materials to DC Public Library Special Collections in March 1997.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">African Americans</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Library of Congress Subject Headings</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="852">
      <subfield code="a">DWP</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="4" ind2="2" tag="856">
      <subfield code="z">Finding aid online:</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">http://washingtoniana.dclibrary.org</subfield>
    </datafield>
  </record>
</marc:collection>

