<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<marc:collection xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/standards/marcxml/schema/MARC21slim.xsd">
  <record>
    <leader>00000npc a2200000 u 4500</leader>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
      <subfield code="a">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">dacs</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="245">
      <subfield code="a">Savoy Family Genealogical Collection</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">1 cubic feet; 1 box</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="546">
      <subfield code="a">English</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="540">
      <subfield code="a">Some material may be copyrighted or restricted. It is the patron's obligation to determine and satisfy copyright or other case restrictions when publishing or otherwise distributing materials found in the collections.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="545">
      <subfield code="a">The Savoy Family Genealogical Collection documents the D.C.-based Savoy family ancestors born between 1794 and 1935, in the eighteenth through the early twentieth century. The life of Edward Augustine Savoy (1855-1943) is documented extensively and has the largest amount of biographical information on his life. The Savoy family descendants contributing the vast majority of the research and information were Wilbur Joseph Duplessis “Buddy” Rogers III, Lauret Edith Savoy, and Patricia Annette Green Wright. All are sixth generation Savoy family descendants.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="2" ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">The biographical narrative of the Savoy family of Washington, D.C. includes information obtained from family members and their records, newspapers articles, excerpts from books, genealogical research, and photographs of members of the Savoy family including photographs of many key events their lives. Digitized and photocopies of book pages and newspaper articles about members of the Savoy family are included in the collection.</subfield>
    </datafield>
  </record>
</marc:collection>

