<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<marc:collection xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/standards/marcxml/schema/MARC21slim.xsd">
  <record>
    <leader>00000npc a2200000 u 4500</leader>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
      <subfield code="a">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">dacs</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="245">
      <subfield code="a">George Washington University "Evolution of Washington's Italian Community, 1890-1980" Oral History Project</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Oral History</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Library of Congress Subject Headings</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">0.25 Linear feet</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="541">
      <subfield code="a">The Center for Washington Area Studies conducted these interviews in 1984 and donated the transcripts for the interviews to the Library in the late 1980s. There is no deed of gift for this collection, but all interviewee releases are granted to the Library.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="545">
      <subfield code="a">The Center for Washington Area Studies (CWAS) was established in 1980 to bring the resources of George Washington University to bear on the development of a fuller understanding of the Washington area as a locality, with its own economy, history, politics, and culture.  In addition, CWAS has supported programs to enrich the collections of the University's Gelman Library related to the Washington area. As a regional studies institute, CWAS' purpose has been to encourage scholarly inquiry, both disciplinary and interdisciplinary, on a broad range of matters relating to the national capital area. The Center has supported faculty and student research, conferences and symposia, and a publications program.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="500">
      <subfield code="a">Processing Information: After the initial donation to the Library, the transcripts were placed in folders and stored them in a filing cabinet with other oral histories. In 2014, the transcripts were digitized and in 2017 the collection was reprocessed. Transcripts were placed into folders and boxed. All administrative documents, including releases, were placed into the control file.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="2" ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">In 1984, the George Washington University Center for Washington Area Studies conducted oral history interviews with members of the Italian community of Washington D.C.. Topics include Italy, immigrating to the United States, family, growing up or living in Washington, D.C., religion, work experience, and the Italian community.  All interviews were a part of a series entitled "Evolution of Washington's Italian Community, 1890-1980." Only three interviews from this series were transferred to the Library. There is a release for Ugo Carusi but not transcript.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="540">
      <subfield code="a">The Library holds copyright for items in this collection with a signed release. There are no restrictions on the use of these collection materials. Reproduction of an oral history without a signed release is not permitted.</subfield>
    </datafield>
  </record>
</marc:collection>

