<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<marc:collection xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:marc="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/standards/marcxml/schema/MARC21slim.xsd http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim">
  <record>
    <leader>00000npcaa2200000 u 4500</leader>
    <controlfield tag="008">190118i1993    xx                  eng d</controlfield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
      <subfield code="a">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">eng</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">DWP</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">dacs</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="0" ind2="7" tag="041">
      <subfield code="a">eng</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">iso639-2b</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="049">
      <subfield code="a">DWP</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="099">
      <subfield code="a">OHP016</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="245">
      <subfield code="a">Northern Shaw Striver Historic Survey Oral History Project,</subfield>
      <subfield code="f">1993</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">0.5</subfield>
      <subfield code="f">Linear feet</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="500">
      <subfield code="a">Processing Information: After the initial donation to the Library, the transcripts were placed in folders and stored them in a filing cabinet with other oral histories. Tapes were duplicated by the Library with use copies being placed a cabinet, while the originals were placed into off-site cold storage. In 2014, the tapes and transcripts were digitized and in 2017 the collection was reprocessed. Transcripts were placed into folders and boxed. Tapes were organized and boxed for long term storage. All administrative documents, including releases, were placed into the control file.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="2" ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">In 1993, Jeff Koenreich conducted these oral histories for the Library's Oral History Project. Residents of the Striver Section of the Shaw neighborhood were interviewed. Topics include the history of the neighborhood, childhood, family, segregation, the Civil Rights movement, and the community.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="540">
      <subfield code="a">The D.C. Public Library does not hold copyright. It is the responsibility of the researcher to obtain permission to publish or exhibit information. Reproduction of oral Histories without release is not permitted.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="541">
      <subfield code="a">Jeff Koenreich conducted these interviews in 1993 and the Tapes and transcripts were transferred to the Library in the mid 1990s. There is no deed of gift for this collection.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="545">
      <subfield code="a">Jeff Koenreich (1954-2008) was born in Salem, Ohio and attended Ohio State University. He came to Washington, D.C. in 1978 and worked for the American Red Cross. A community organizer he helped found the Cardozo Shaw Neighborhood Association and led an effort to restore the Lincoln Theatre.</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Oral History</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Library of Congress Subject Headings</subfield>
    </datafield>
    <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="852">
      <subfield code="a">DWP</subfield>
    </datafield>
  </record>
</marc:collection>

